I want to talk to you guys about making
bio-hybrid robotics because it is so
much more than just making nightmare
robots. And yes, nightmare robots are
part of the deal, but it's also doing a
whole lot of good. Very uncanny and
possibly disturbing good, but still
good. And we'll talk about it.
Biohybrids come in a wide variety of
forms. In fact, we are already using
them for medicine right now. We
genetically engineer viruses so that
they can geneedit people. That has been
done. It's been done with cickle cell
anemia. This group is taking algae and
then converting it into a biohybrid
robot that can then deliver medicine.
Now, I'm not particularly fond of algae,
mainly because they produce byproducts
that can cause ALS. In fact, even living
near a body of water can increase your
chances of getting ALS significantly,
which is a neurogenerative condition.
So, I just have a thing against algae.
But yeah, it works. And this is why
lipids are such a big deal, lipid nano
particles, because you can shove them
full of stuff and then those can enter
your cells directly. Your cells are
covered in lipid billayer. It makes a
little circle and then you have to get
past that in order to get into the cell.
In fact, research on lipid
nanoparticles, so protocells have been
very effective for both figuring out the
origins of life, but also medicine
because your cells are just goop inside
of lipid. More recently, researchers
have been working on making organs or
limbs, parts of a whole body because you
can grow them independently and then
they can be put together like Legos and
yes, a synthetic lung maybe in the
future for us. Also work on kidneys and
livers, but research in those seems to
be better to just grow mini versions of
them because they can still kind of do
the same job. I think the living body
robots are kind of the creepiest ones.
Like muscle fiber wrapped around a
little spring so that it can move and
even be directed. It's just uncanny
because technically made of human
tissue, but it's not in a human. But
this could be part of a limb. Yes, you
could potentially grow a limb, assemble
it, and then use it as opposed to one
you might not have. Hell, maybe you can
have multiple limbs. I don't know. I
don't know that the structure is there,
but I bet someone's going to try it. I
mean, you do technically already have
multiple limbs. I mean, more than four.
This is one of the papers that just
generally creeped people out because
they made a biomechanical hand. It's
made out of human tissue, mind you. They
grew muscle fibers and put it together
and made each individual finger so that
they could move like our own hands. And
we've all seen the flesh thing that I
love so much. Also made from human
tissues that they wanted to become a
skin for robots that could potentially
grow, heal, and give sensation. Although
there have been better alternatives, and
I've talked about them, like carbon nano
fibers than your robot needing flesh.
And because people always ask, we are on
the verge of biopunk. You can get
cybernetic enhancements. You can get
them right now. People are getting brain
chips. If you want a future where you
can have a tail or cat ears, I guess you
can have it. I don't know why you would
want it. Maybe I don't want to know why,
but I don't see why it's not possible.
So, yes, I do adore the creepy side of
science, and I'm never going to stop
talking about it, but there's good
things happening, too. When the robots
rebel, I'll probably be the person to
tell you about it. Follow for more.